<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>A.J.</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
 <updated>2017-07-18T21:41:54-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>
 <author>
   <name>A.J. Kueterman</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Little Films</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/18/little-films/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/18/little-films</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apple does this incredibly effective thing where they put advertisements from TV up online and market them as &lt;em&gt;films&lt;/em&gt; and yet they are always so well made it’s hard to argue with that description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shot-on-iphone&quot;&gt;Shot on iPhone&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite series that they did over the last few years was the &lt;em&gt;Shot on iPhone 6&lt;/em&gt; series of ads, where they simply aired 15 second videos made by iPhone users as TV spots.  Most of the videos highlighted the then-new slow motion or time-lapse video features, but all of them were visually stunning and excitingly punchy ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled out a few of my favorites that were aired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trond-k&quot;&gt;Trond K&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y3s17H5hb-Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hajime-i&quot;&gt;Hajime I&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v07wrzGPeaU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jin-c&quot;&gt;Jin C&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX5eEv-F6nw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;araby-p&quot;&gt;Araby P&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/son7gyOfE6A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love these videos because they inspire anyone who has a smartphone to go make a film.  The only tool you really need is in your pocket.  Not only that, but each ad shows how you can tell a story in a single shot that may span only a dozen seconds.  Something about breaking it down to that achievable level makes you want to go out and do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aj-k&quot;&gt;A.J. K.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b6Z16KALm98&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might not be time lapse of an incredible mountain range or drone-enabled photography of a seagull, but it managed to make ‘art’ out of an everyday commute, which I thought was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-else&quot;&gt;What Else&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t just write this article to point out how I made a video that I’m still proud of - although it’s definitely partly that - I also just wanted to share the emotional strength of a beautiful picture or video.  Regardless of the grandeur of our daily surroundings, there’s always a way to find beauty.  When it can be captured and shared, all the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be hard to separate the monolithic corporation from the high-minded, free-thinking vision of these ads, but if you can what you see is some beautiful memories captured by people all around the world.  The romantic idea that we are all connected by a beautiful and benevolent device is alluring at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let yourself appreciate the beautiful work of your iPhone-enabled peers, and remember to stay true to the vision.  The camera is a liar but it can spin some beautiful tales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;405&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YpUa7YvhUJo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Link Dump (also hi)</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/07/12/link-dump/"/>
   <updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/12/link-dump</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;First, a moment to say &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/code&gt; yet again as I rebuild this blog once more &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;link-dump&quot;&gt;Link Dump&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been consuming &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; voraciously and done a lot more long reading in the last month or so.  I came across a few good articles to share that I just haven’t gotten a chance to share yet.  I’m just going to toss them in here as a list of recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-secret-origin-story-of-the-iphone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/13/15782200/one-device-secret-history-iphone-brian-merchant-book-excerpt&quot;&gt;The Secret Origin Story of the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from a book by Brian Merchant - “&lt;em&gt;The One Device: The Secret History of the iPhone&lt;/em&gt;”.  The book is a deep look at how the iconic device got made.  I was in rapture as I read this excerpt on The Verge, and I immediately went out and pre-ordered it.  I’ll try to do a mini-review of the whole work after I get to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first few chapters I can tell you its not just the politics and intrigue of the iPhone’s creating at Apple, but also a sprawling investigation into the physical construction of the iPhone and its impact on the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-finish-tomb-for-nuclear-waste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/olkiluoto-island-finland-nuclear-waste-onkalo&quot;&gt;The Finish Tomb for Nuclear Waste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a really awesome article I ran across on HN a few weeks ago.  It is a story about the construction of a massive permanant nuclear waste storage facility being built on Olkiluoto Island in western Finland.  The repository, called Onkalo, is built to last for 100,000 years - enough time to allow the toxic waste within de-radiate.  It’s an eerie tale about human discovery and the ramifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;android-viewmodel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/architecture/viewmodel.html&quot;&gt;Android &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ViewModel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that has my attention the most coming out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.google.com/io/recap/&quot;&gt;Google I/O&lt;/a&gt; was the substantial architecture changes coming to Android in O.  This link is basically a reminder for myself to learn more about it and hopefully share how I use it in my own development.  For now, take a look at what they can do for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one minute gist is you can now have Lifecycle-aware components that survive for the lifecycle of your activity and can be used to manage data for your Activities and their Fragments in a much cleaner and safer way then the previous patterns.  Implement a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ViewModel&lt;/code&gt; and implement listeners to its members and you can create clean reactive Fragments easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thats-it-for-now&quot;&gt;That’s it for now…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come with this blog.  For now it’s a simpler more cleaner site setup that I can hopefully be vigilant in updating moving forward.  Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-AJ&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
