<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>AJ Kueterman</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Lego Ideas</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Lego Saturn V launched just last month to universal excitement and praise, and it has been damn near impossible since to snag one firsthand.  Just another success story from the Lego Ideas project, the website that allows Lego fans to design their own Lego sets.  Users can search for and vote on their favorite designs, and the winning designs get an official treatment from Lego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Lego Ideas project that became the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.lego.com/en-US/LEGO-NASA-Apollo-Saturn-V-21309&quot;&gt;Saturn V set&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/7b5/24e/76841/1562933-o_18vmhs3t8tivs4a1vuh15mk1s95c-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;saturn v project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The final set&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://sh-s7-live-s.legocdn.com/is/image/LEGO/21309?id=K7eR72&amp;amp;fmt=jpg&amp;amp;fit=constrain,1&amp;amp;wid=1200&amp;amp;hei=900&amp;amp;qlt=80,1&amp;amp;op_sharpen=0&amp;amp;resMode=sharp2&amp;amp;op_usm=1,1,6,0&amp;amp;iccEmbed=0&amp;amp;printRes=72&quot; alt=&quot;saturn v&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took a look through the current selection of up and coming Lego Ideas sets and pulled out a few of my favs just for kicks.  Take a look and be sure to vote on the ones you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nasa-space-shuttle&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/50a447cc-0acb-4fff-b3c9-41739fed157c/updates&quot;&gt;NASA Space Shuttle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/50a/447/4644435-06_Shuttle_Landing2-fbNm80Dqd0oPaA-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Landing Shuttle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously looking to capitalize on the success of the Saturn V, the NASA Space Shuttle set idea is simply that.  The space shuttle has been designed to be equal in scale (1/110) to the Saturn V, and includes seven shuttle crew members in flight and spacewalking suits as well as the Canadarm shuttle arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/50a/447/4644139-05_Shuttle_Canadarm2-Wu-Ivsti2fVSuQ-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canadarm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The set is pretty cool, it’s biggest flaw probably being that Lego already released a space shuttle set with similar features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/50a/447/4655406-07_Shuttle_NewComps_7-16-OU0Lm-ep_S3c8A-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Shuttle Comparison&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results are promising for now though, so check it out to see what you think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anatomini&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/a7687039-bb20-45f4-b8e4-11619720245c&quot;&gt;Anatomini&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This set is an interesting one, and one of the most complex I came across during my rundown.  It’s called Anatomini, and it’s a large-scale minifigure including enclosed skeleton and internal organs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/a76/870/4631621-Anatomini_text_16-cU51eLDkJ5-1oQ-thumbnail-full.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Main Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this set is awesome, and the complexity of the internal organs and technic skeleton make it look like an awesome build.  That said, I doubt its feasibility with Lego proper.  It might be pushing it with the general vibe of Lego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/a76/870/4631581-Anatomini_text_06-MFdoobaXsEkgZA-thumbnail-full.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something about tearing open the ribcage of a minifig to find the anatomically correct guts inside seems a bit too adult or physical for a full scale $200+ Lego set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/a76/870/4631601-Anatomini_text_11-aF65PO0RYvKzgA-thumbnail-full.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;Ribcage&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, I’m rooting for it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;old-diner-with-arcade&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/5995b5f7-6955-4a57-9315-9f78f9410f80&quot;&gt;Old Diner with Arcade&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next set that caught my eye was this 80’s style Diner/Arcade set, roughly in the style of the Modulars sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/599/5b5/4473841-1-WpVUQrofLWw7gw-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;Main diner pic&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This set is here largely in part to its awesome set rendering.  I’m not sure what rendering tools are used by set builders site-wide, but this one is one of the most beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/599/5b5/4473769-3-tKy1VXarrZqX7w-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;full interior&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly, just look at the lighting and detail on these close up shots.  They are impossibly pristine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/599/5b5/4473773-4-W58x6woCd2SAPQ-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;close up shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more, hard to stop staring at that shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/599/5b5/4473821-9-oMfqSaVYr60RWQ-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;milkshake maker&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The set is lighthearted and intricate, and would be an amazing minifig-scaled build for those Modular fans.  If I had any critique it would be the size.  I would hope for a slightly bumped-up scale when Lego refines.  I have a lot of love and support for this set.  Check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;great-white-shark&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/6c529a2d-f745-44c2-8a4d-88aaa2322c90&quot;&gt;Great White Shark&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ocean’s most feared predator, now floating an inch above your coffee table.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/66e/d70/153741/2652300-o_1asho41hu19t5p6s1acd1i2selpg-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;main shark photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I have grown older I’ve started to gravitate to the more mature-looking sets like Lego Architecture or certain Ideas sets like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.lego.com/en-GB/Birds-21301&quot;&gt;Lego Ideas Birds&lt;/a&gt; set.  That’s the vibe of this set, while retaining the fun with a well-placed minifig.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/66e/d70/153741/2652306-o_1asho4grevhtlve1f821ctlfi7u-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;front shark photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This particular Ideas designer also has a few other cool sharks sets that would be worth the look as well.  The Great White is just the de-facto favorite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hammerhead&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/54ee2d19-0e48-4a3c-960b-8b4dd81b33a5&quot;&gt;Hammerhead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/64b/080/153668/2651760-o_1asfv752d1tn1rqg1od71f0g1o6q7-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;hammerhead photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;orca-and-penguins&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/b950dd7c-eb4d-4b17-9a43-b0c4889e13e0&quot;&gt;Orca and Penguins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/905/8e6/163869/2802574-o_1b5o1pecqa5l17aqlmg1ce68rg1f-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;orca photo&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you check these sets out and browse for your own favorites on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/dashboard&quot;&gt;Ideas site&lt;/a&gt;.  For Lego fans, browsing the creativity of the community is a lot of fun, and the possibility that your favorites could someday be in your hands is an exciting prospect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ones-that-made-it&quot;&gt;The ones that made it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To wrap it up, check out these awesome sets that are already in &lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/discover#search/f:projectStateFilter=in_review/s:most_recent/n:24&quot;&gt;Lego Review status&lt;/a&gt;.  They’re all awesome designs and I hope the powers that be pick some good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vokswagen-golf-mk1-gti&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/35dacd9d-fb79-4048-a39f-199d56d8a8eb&quot;&gt;Vokswagen Golf MK1 GTI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/658/712/155745/2686803-o_1aukbsfk41j4l1lvk101udvn1qb1c-thumbnail-full.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;vw golf&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-iron-giant&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/2948cb06-a9b8-4fe7-9191-583257643714&quot;&gt;The Iron Giant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/944/3fb/158671/2727670-o_1b191tm5ht5igb8p101crf1m5p5p-thumbnail-full.png&quot; alt=&quot;iron giant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reys-speeder-ucs&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/projects/1dc7fc2b-1503-4a85-85e0-56546e634b63&quot;&gt;Rey’s Speeder UCS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://dp1eoqdp1qht7.cloudfront.net/community/projects/db6/b42/144406/2503673-o_1al5dqi8v45t1mdu19ri1r2f617d-thumbnail-full.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;reys speeder&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017-07-25/lego-ideas-roundup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017-07-25/lego-ideas-roundup/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Little Films</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple does this incredibly effective thing where they put advertisements from TV up online and market them as &lt;em&gt;films&lt;/em&gt; and yet they are always so well made it’s hard to argue with that description.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;shot-on-iphone&quot;&gt;Shot on iPhone&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite series that they did over the last few years was the &lt;em&gt;Shot on iPhone 6&lt;/em&gt; series of ads, where they simply aired 15 second videos made by iPhone users as TV spots.  Most of the videos highlighted the then-new slow motion or time-lapse video features, but all of them were visually stunning and excitingly punchy ads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pulled out a few of my favorites that were aired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trond-k&quot;&gt;Trond K&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y3s17H5hb-Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hajime-i&quot;&gt;Hajime I&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/v07wrzGPeaU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jin-c&quot;&gt;Jin C&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OX5eEv-F6nw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;araby-p&quot;&gt;Araby P&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/son7gyOfE6A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love these videos because they inspire anyone who has a smartphone to go make a film.  The only tool you really need is in your pocket.  Not only that, but each ad shows how you can tell a story in a single shot that may span only a dozen seconds.  Something about breaking it down to that achievable level makes you want to go out and do it yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s exactly what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aj-k&quot;&gt;A.J. K.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b6Z16KALm98&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Might not be time lapse of an incredible mountain range or drone-enabled photography of a seagull, but it managed to make ‘art’ out of an everyday commute, which I thought was exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-else&quot;&gt;What Else&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t just write this article to point out how I made a video that I’m still proud of - although it’s definitely partly that - I also just wanted to share the emotional strength of a beautiful picture or video.  Regardless of the grandeur of our daily surroundings, there’s always a way to find beauty.  When it can be captured and shared, all the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be hard to separate the monolithic corporation from the high-minded, free-thinking vision of these ads, but if you can what you see is some beautiful memories captured by people all around the world.  The romantic idea that we are all connected by a beautiful and benevolent device is alluring at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let yourself appreciate the beautiful work of your iPhone-enabled peers, and remember to stay true to the vision.  The camera is a liar but it can spin some beautiful tales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;videoWrapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YpUa7YvhUJo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017-07-18/little-films/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017-07-18/little-films/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Link Dump (also hi)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;First, a moment to say &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Hello World!&lt;/code&gt; yet again as I rebuild this blog once more &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;link-dump&quot;&gt;Link Dump&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been consuming &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.ycombinator.com/&quot;&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; voraciously and done a lot more long reading in the last month or so.  I came across a few good articles to share that I just haven’t gotten a chance to share yet.  I’m just going to toss them in here as a list of recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-secret-origin-story-of-the-iphone&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/6/13/15782200/one-device-secret-history-iphone-brian-merchant-book-excerpt&quot;&gt;The Secret Origin Story of the iPhone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an excerpt from a book by Brian Merchant - “&lt;em&gt;The One Device: The Secret History of the iPhone&lt;/em&gt;”.  The book is a deep look at how the iconic device got made.  I was in rapture as I read this excerpt on The Verge, and I immediately went out and pre-ordered it.  I’ll try to do a mini-review of the whole work after I get to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the first few chapters I can tell you its not just the politics and intrigue of the iPhone’s creating at Apple, but also a sprawling investigation into the physical construction of the iPhone and its impact on the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-finish-tomb-for-nuclear-waste&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.co.uk/article/olkiluoto-island-finland-nuclear-waste-onkalo&quot;&gt;The Finish Tomb for Nuclear Waste&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a really awesome article I ran across on HN a few weeks ago.  It is a story about the construction of a massive permanant nuclear waste storage facility being built on Olkiluoto Island in western Finland.  The repository, called Onkalo, is built to last for 100,000 years - enough time to allow the toxic waste within de-radiate.  It’s an eerie tale about human discovery and the ramifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;android-viewmodel&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.android.com/topic/libraries/architecture/viewmodel.html&quot;&gt;Android &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ViewModel&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that has my attention the most coming out of &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.google.com/io/recap/&quot;&gt;Google I/O&lt;/a&gt; was the substantial architecture changes coming to Android in O.  This link is basically a reminder for myself to learn more about it and hopefully share how I use it in my own development.  For now, take a look at what they can do for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one minute gist is you can now have Lifecycle-aware components that survive for the lifecycle of your activity and can be used to manage data for your Activities and their Fragments in a much cleaner and safer way then the previous patterns.  Implement a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ViewModel&lt;/code&gt; and implement listeners to its members and you can create clean reactive Fragments easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;thats-it-for-now&quot;&gt;That’s it for now…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come with this blog.  For now it’s a simpler more cleaner site setup that I can hopefully be vigilant in updating moving forward.  Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-AJ&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017-07-12/link-dump/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017-07-12/link-dump/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
