<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A.J. Kueterman</title>
    <description>Development, design, film, television, music, culture, science, art, and all of those other good things.  This is my personal blog, we&#39;ll see what it becomes.</description>
    <link>http://ajkueterman.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ajkueterman.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 10:44:24 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 10:44:24 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asus ZenBook 3 - The Newest MacBook Killer</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;asus-zenbook-3---the-newest-macbook-killer&quot;&gt;Asus ZenBook 3 - The Newest MacBook Killer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Asus ZenBook 3 and MacBook are interchangeable for ‘any Competitor’ and ‘Apple product’, respectively)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just finished re-watching Danny Boyle and Aaron Sorkin’s &lt;em&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/em&gt;.  If you haven’t seen it, it’s an excellent film that I highly recommend, and some very nice borderline Apple-propaganda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verge published &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/5/30/11810132/asus-zenbook-3-apple-macbook-photo-comparison&quot;&gt;this story&lt;/a&gt; showing how the Asus ZenBook 3 stands up visually with the MacBook.  They also mention an important point, and that is how obviously &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/circuitbreaker/2016/5/30/11810152/asus-zenbook-3-release-date-price-specs-computex-2016&quot;&gt;this computer is aimed at Apple’s MacBook&lt;/a&gt;.  It attempts to do what PC makers have always done to attack Apple computers - out spec them.  The idea is that if you compare the spec sheets by the numbers you’d have to be crazy to pick Apple hardware over their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record, it hasn’t really helped all that much.  Because the fact is there’s a lot more that goes into buying a computer that strictly specs for most people, and right now Apple is making consumers feel confident in spending money on Apple.  I think, more than hardcore specs, it comes down to design and Mac OS that pushes people into buying Macs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean let’s talk about design.  The MacBook looks exceedingly cooler than the ZenBook 3.  That matte aluminum finish and the mirrored Apple logo is brilliantly minimalistic.  ZenBook has that weird reflective backplate with the utilitarian ASUS logo.  The keyboard of the ZenBook, while Asus has stepped it’s game up for this PC in that regard, can hardly compare to the Apple keyboard visual standard.  Then you have design flourishes like the speakers on the ZenBook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZUoazJBQS3A3YuhC-Iii5JdJX3A=/1020x0/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6564697/DSCF4312.0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ZenBook 3 Speakers&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;ASUS ZenBook 3 speakers and keyboard design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, they just don’t really work.  And that’s the thing when it comes down to buying an ultrabook like this.  You’re not buying it for power, you’re not buying it to break into Windows’ OS (same goes for the MacBook, in all honesty it’s still a silly purchase for a primary PC in my opinion), and if you really need portability there are options like the Surface or much cheaper options that have more flexible port configurations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why would you buy one of these ultrabooks?  I think it comes down to design.  Basically, you buy this PC because you want to show it off.  You want the newest, thinnest, purposefully designed device.  It’s a status symbol.  So that means, for well over a thousand dollars, you expect the pinnacle of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, it’s still hard to beat Apple’s design for the Macs.  So, &lt;em&gt;IF&lt;/em&gt; I had the capital to drop on a auxiliary PC that looks amazing and performs my laptop’s normal tasks - I would still buy a MacBook.  I have yet to see a PC that would convince me otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/pc/macbook/apple/asus/zenbook/2016/04/04/ASUS-zenbook-MacBook-killer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/pc/macbook/apple/asus/zenbook/2016/04/04/ASUS-zenbook-MacBook-killer.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>pc</category>
        
        <category>macbook</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>asus</category>
        
        <category>zenbook</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trump Camp vs. Establishment &#39;Bull Shit&#39;</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The TRUMP campaign’s senior advisor Barry Bennet wrote an internal memo on April 2nd - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-politics/wp/2016/04/04/internal-memo-reveals-trump-campaigns-mounting-fury-with-its-critics/&quot;&gt;published by the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; - that bashed the media and Republican establishment on their TRUMP-focused criticisms that seemingly reached a head in the past week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the memo with subject reading “&lt;em&gt;Digging through the Bull Shit&lt;/em&gt;”, Bennett calls out the media’s overt targeting of TRUMP and retorts that despite their media hits TRUMP continues to rise in the polls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mr. Bennett is ready to frame this as a victory despite the odds, I see it a little differently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When every news outlet exposes TRUMP’s flaws, in both conservative and mainstream media, does that really speak to your strength as a candidate?  Or does it rather highlight the issues on which he falters as a candidate for most voters?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be my more moderate-to-left standpoint - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/4/1/11340882/republicans-democrats-media-fox&quot;&gt;more likely to see the mainstream media as factually accurate and reliable&lt;/a&gt; - but I just don’t understand how so many voters can see blatantly defying information sources as a sign that their viewpoint is fair and accurate.  When everyone who knows anything about politics is reporting that TRUMP is a deeply flawed and divisive candidate, what makes you think you know better?  Gut feel and an blind patriotism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I might be more annoyed with the apparent idiocy of such a large chunk of the GOP voter base and the entire TRUMP campaign than Barry is with the establishment “Bull Shit”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ps&quot;&gt;P.S.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/blogs/2016-gop-primary-live-updates-and-results/2016/04/donald-trump-foreign-policy-experts-221528&quot;&gt;this article on Politico&lt;/a&gt; later in the day.  This TRUMP quote just about sums it up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“You know, I’ve always wanted to say this—I’ve never said this before with all the talking we all do—all of these experts, ‘Oh we need an expert—’ &lt;strong&gt;The experts are terrible&lt;/strong&gt;,” he declared. “Look at the mess we’re in with all these experts that we have. Look at the mess. Look at the Middle East. &lt;strong&gt;If our presidents and our politicians went on vacation for 365 days a year and went to the beach, we’d be in much better shape right now&lt;/strong&gt; in the Middle East.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fucking drivel.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/politico/politics/trump/2016/04/04/trump-unloads-on-media.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/politico/politics/trump/2016/04/04/trump-unloads-on-media.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politico</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>Trump</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>State of the GOP - A Personal Analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It interests me how blinded people are to external realities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent the weekend at my extended family’s farm.  There, opinions echo back and forth in the isolation.  Homes are separated by miles, and communities are held together by religious practices familial bonds.  They hear messages from the outside, but from outsiders.  Their lives are built around a moral code handed down to them from neighbors, parents, and priests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an interesting world to walk into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My family, who live mostly in the suburbs of a small-to-medium sized city, are seen as the ‘city folks’.  By definition we don’t understand the lives and the values of their culture.  How could we?  My parents are still very much a part of this mentality, but their children have never lived that life.  Our bonds to that mindset are tenuous.  I see more than one point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all a lot of prologue to a topic not quite so existential (though maybe it is) - the GOP position in Washington right now and the mindsets that affect it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-gop-and-their-image-problem&quot;&gt;The GOP and their image problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GOP, despite their dominance in the legislature of late, is in a time of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is named Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other is a lot more existential, and needs to be described with a bit more history - although it goes hand-in-hand with the rise of Trump.  That is, the image problem the Republican Party has with it’s conservative base.  A base that has been promised action on their steadfast conservative goals, and consistently let down by their elected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/3/9/11182590/obamacare-donald-trump&quot;&gt;article in &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; a while ago, that talked a bit about Obamacare and how it was the Republican response to Obamacare that helped to cause this massive polarization of the GOP and this intense battle between Republican legislative groups, rather than Obamacare itself.  Essentially, what has happened is that the GOP rose up in arms - along with groups like the Tea Party - in a massive opposition to Obamacare and the progressive steps the government had taken in the first years of the Obama presidency.  Republican candidates ran on a promise to reverse the actions taken by Obama and to repeal Obamacare.  They won with this promise.  Then, year after year, they failed to deliver on their promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not really the fault of these individual men and women that they couldn’t repeal Obamacare.  The fact is that it would have been extremely difficult to reverse the progress made after it has been put in place.  The GOP arguably knew this all along, but even if not, they are dealing with that fact now.  To many Republican voters, their elected have failed them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we have the GOP ‘Establishment’ who have basically been working to maintain leadership in their party by fighting for what they believe are true Republican ideals.  They’re doing this by guarding traditional conservative economic ideals by creating economically conservative legislation or by blocking progressive legislature - but are continuing to let down their electorate by not delivering the impossible that they promised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is you have this huge conglomerate of Republican or conservative voters out here who have deeply held opinions on what their government should or shouldn’t be - what their country should and shouldn’t look like.  In their eyes important issues to them are being overlooked, bad deals are being made, promises are being broken, and even where establishment ideals mesh with theirs little is being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I hear complaints about from my very conservative, religious family:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Obamacare is bad and should go away (isn’t going to happen, at least not how they’d like)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Defund Planned Parenthood and repeal Roe V. Wade (can’t imagine this is plausible, but regressions in this area are troubling)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fight ISIS aka Fight Muslims - whether they know they are saying that or not (fear mongering is working, and my very religious family is very willing to blame an ideology they don’t understand)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Just generally get Obama out of the White House and restore the world to an order where we can keep ourselves from teetering on the edge of the pits of Hell and eternal darkness.  Again, fear mongering.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t hear so much about the economy and creating more tax breaks for their tax bracket - though this underpins much of it - my family is more concerned with the social order of this country that they believe in, and that they believe is slipping away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we have a fundamental problem when we talk about compromising with Democrats on legislation.  There is this belief that we must stand firm on our conservative grounds.  Pass nothing (except tax breaks).  Repeal progress made over the last decade in healthcare, in education.  Undo the social norm we as a country have come to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gop-v-scotus&quot;&gt;GOP V. SCOTUS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What initially spurred this now-rambling blog post is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2016/03/supreme-court-conservatives-mcconnell-221161&quot;&gt;article in &lt;em&gt;Politico&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the reaction to the GOP Establishment’s call to block Obama’s Supreme Court nomination of judge Merrick Garland, and about the potential backlash that would ensue if Mitch McConnell and the rest of the establishment backtracked on their blockade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, what we’ve run into is a similar issue.  On the one hand you have conservatives and elites who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2016/03/redstates-scotus-wva-221226&quot;&gt;don’t necessarily agree with McConnell and crew&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2016/03/poll-senate-supreme-court-nominee-221168&quot;&gt;blocking this SCOTUS nomination&lt;/a&gt; (at least outright denying to hear anything about it), and on the other hand you have conservatives applauding this steady and unwavering stance taken by the party leadership (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.politico.com/story/2016/03/supreme-court-conservatives-mcconnell-221161&quot;&gt;threatening against&lt;/a&gt; any concessions).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;McConnell and the more pragmatic Republican leaders are trying to walk this tightrope.  They don’t want to seem like they aren’t doing anything, and they also don’t want to look like they’re wavering in the face of pressure from liberals.  It’s an unenviable position, no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So when it boils down to it, we basically have a fragmented GOP base who is hardlined on a lot of social issues that are very hard to address in the way they imagine, and a GOP leadership more interested in making conservative plays in areas they appreciate (and likely think their electorate will appreciate).  The leaders are in a tough spot because doing nothing is bad, but doing anything bi-partisan is also bad.  Meanwhile, this conservative base is growing more and more restless with their actions or inactions or compromised action that they’re ready for a complete upheaval of the whole system (which I still don’t really understand).  Enter Donald J. Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;trump-mania&quot;&gt;TRUMP mania&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to do a whole blog post part 2 on Trump here, but it’s interesting how he plays in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GOP leaders and legislators are paralyzed by fragmentation in the party.  This paralysis is angering voters, and compromise in response to this anger is further angering voters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the GOP ‘Establishment’ and the elected leaders can’t be trusted.  To the voters, they need someone with the balls to stand up and take charge and &lt;em&gt;deliver&lt;/em&gt; on their calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To them, this is Trump.  It almost makes sense.  It’s &lt;em&gt;almost&lt;/em&gt; relatable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is this man they have chosen to take up their charge is a racist, a misogynist, a liar, a dope, a bully, and a fraud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I don’t understand.  How can people (like my own parents) who value social issues like being anti-abortion and religious protections as much or more than economic or immigration or foreign policy issues can choose Trump of all people to be their standard bearer?  The man isn’t religious, is literally running on tearing down religious liberty, and breaks from the conservative right mostly on social or religious issues like his stance on Israel or his stance on Planned Parenthood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s this whole terrifying thing of us versus them.  This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/3/1/11127424/trump-authoritarianism&quot;&gt;authoritarian viewpoint of the world&lt;/a&gt; that people right now are unfortunately drawn to, that frankly I just don’t understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m actually more sympathetic to authoritarianism than I’d probably like to admit.  The difference between me and many Americans is that I don’t think we’re in the danger that they think we are in.  We don’t need to turn to this destructive mindset.  Not ever, but especially not now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re Americans.  We’re living in one of the greatest countries on the planet in our time and place.  Our economy is better now than it was  when Obama first took office.  We’re getting paid more, more of us are working, and we are systematically more tolerant and welcoming than we have been in many ways.  What then, is this huge uproar truly about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it’s about this narrative spun by the right.  The narrative that Obama is the wrong man for the job.  That his attempt at offering more Americans proper medical care was a massive overreach in executive power by liberals in government.  That the GOP has lost control of the country they held.  That the only way to keep things the way they like them is to burn the whole thing down - to reject all who threaten their regressive way of life.  To be more hostile, less welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a terrifying trend.  I just wish we could wake up from this misplaced, apocalyptic fervor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-final-tldr&quot;&gt;A final TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a true mess of a blog post (it was cathartic at least), but if you read it I hope you can see where I’m coming from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR - The GOP has spun a self serving narrative that has turned self destructive.  Trump is a horrible human being and should be discarded and forgotten so America can realize how great it is, and progress towards a better future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/politico/politics/trump/gop/republican/2016/03/28/political-musing-one.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/politico/politics/trump/gop/republican/2016/03/28/political-musing-one.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politico</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>Trump</category>
        
        <category>GOP</category>
        
        <category>Republican</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vox Article Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the wake of what seems like a barrage of primary debates over the course of the last few weeks I have been devouring articles on the race and on political themes and policy voraciously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the most interesting articles came from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favorite political news sites.  &lt;em&gt;Vox&lt;/em&gt; specializes in explainer journalism, breaking down issues and explaining policy in more of a straightforward style - like very professional political blog posts but with less opinion based writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I read a series of really good articles that I feel I have to share.  They all follow a loosely similar theme - analyzing major changes in the political landscape and/or explaining historical changes that have brought us to this point.  The loose themes are Neoconservatism and the state of the Republican Party as well as, more broadly, U.S. Foreign Policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;here-are-the-articles-i-recommend-reading&quot;&gt;Here are the articles I recommend reading&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are listed chronologically and, coincidentally, in the order in which I read them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/2/16/11022104/iraq-war-neoconservatives&quot;&gt;America’s unlearned lesson: the forgotten truth about why we invaded Iraq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2016/3/9/11182590/obamacare-donald-trump&quot;&gt;Obamacare didn’t pave the way for Donald Trump. The GOP’s response to it did.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/3/10/11189350/twilight-of-the-neoconservatives&quot;&gt;Twilight of the neoconservatives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/3/10/11194036/obama-worldview-atlantic&quot;&gt;The best articulation yet of how President Obama sees the world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heres-my-tldr-overviews&quot;&gt;Here’s my TL;DR overviews:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first article sets the stage for explaining kind of the rise of Neoconservatism and its impact on the invasion of Iraq and how that shaped the trajectory of U.S. interests in the Middle East and our Foreign Policy over the last two decades.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The second article pivots to the domestic issue of Obamacare, and responds to another article blaming the political polarization in America on Obamacare.  The argument instead is that the Republican leadership’s pitch to their electorate - that Obamacare was a partisan effort to sideline the democratic process and shove a partisan policy down the throats of the Republican electorate - has backfired in recent years as the Republican ‘establishment’ has failed to undo the early work done in the President’s first term.  It’s relevant to the race, as we see the Republican electorate basically getting fed up with these ‘establishment’ types who have failed to deliver on their promises in their eyes (promises that were probably not very honest to begin with).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This article kind of jumps off the platform built in the first article.  It follows the rise and fall of Neoconservatism as a political ideology and as a powerhouse in the Republican party.  It helps to explain the current state of the party as well as the Trump-fueled schism happening now around that viewpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I read this article this morning.  It’s a look at President Obama’s Foriegn Policy world view.  His so-called ‘Hobbesian Optimism’ about America and how that has shaped his actions during his presidency.  I really enjoyed  reading it, probably because my own personal views on foreign policy tend to mirror those same themes of general optimism with shades of curmudgeonly hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it this week!  Hope you enjoy reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/vox/politics/2016/03/11/vox-article-dump.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/vox/politics/2016/03/11/vox-article-dump.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>vox</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 88th Academy Awards</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Or, “How I Learned to Stop Caring and Live With The Oscars”…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another year in film has come and gone, marked with the craft’s most prestigious awards ceremony, The Oscars.  It’s an awesome occasion every year to celebrate the best work in cinema in the past year, and watch the Academy voters miss the mark everywhere on wins after botching nods in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a little cynical, but not too cynical to enjoy all the pomp and circumstance or get unnecessarily excited when a favorite gets a win and gets their chance to celebrate on stage.
Before I jump into my reactions, it’s also important to note that this was the year the Academy’s consistent snubbing of black artists’ work came to a head, with many high profile black celebrities deciding to boycott the awards.  With #OscarsSoWhite trending on Twitter, host Chris Rock was left steering the show amidst the controversy.  He came out swinging, hitting the controversy head on, and filling the room with gloriously nervous laughter from the, I’ll say &lt;em&gt;dramatically&lt;/em&gt;, nearly-all white audience.  Hopefully, the Academy voters wake up to the world they live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, without further ado, here’s A.J.’s rating of the winners and losers from the 88th Academy Awards:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mad-max-is-awesome-and-deserves-all-the-awards-it-earned&quot;&gt;Mad Max is awesome, and deserves all the awards it earned.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mad Max: Fury Road&lt;/em&gt; won awards for Best Makeup, Costume Design, Sound Mixing, Sound Editing, Film Editing, and Production Design, racking up a grand total of six awards for the most won of the night.  I think Mad Max was one of the best, most impressive films of this past year, and definitely deserved the recognition it got.  My only grumble is that it swept all the least exciting, most technical awards of the night, like the Academy wanted to make a point about its quality while letting it remain out of the limelight of the &lt;em&gt;real&lt;/em&gt; awards.  This might be the cynicism talking though, I’m very happy for their well deserved wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lubezki-wins-his-third-statue-in-a-row-for-best-cinematography-as-i-weep-for-roger-deakins&quot;&gt;Lubezki wins his THIRD statue in a row for Best Cinematography, as I weep for Roger Deakins.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emmanuel Lubezki is a supremely skilled DP and &lt;em&gt;The Revenant&lt;/em&gt; was definitely one of the most beautiful films of the year.  His cinematography is always mind-blowingly beautiful, and his technical and artistic aptitude deserves to be cherished.  His style also sort of sets him up for this award, because I feel like even people who don’t put a premium on cinematography when watching films can always spot his dramatic, overt approach to filming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m setting this up because I am very torn as well.  Roger Deakins was also nominated for Best Cinematography this year for his work on Sicario which was a solid film that would have been forgettable if not for his work.  Roger Deakins has been nominated &lt;strong&gt;thirteen&lt;/strong&gt; times for his work between 1994 and 2015, and has &lt;em&gt;never won&lt;/em&gt;.  If you’ve ever seen any of his work you would understand and be as outraged as I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR:  Happy for Lubezki, but the systematic snubbing of Roger Deakins is &lt;em&gt;criminal&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tom-hardy-was-the-best-supporting-actor-mark-rylance-won-instead&quot;&gt;Tom Hardy was the best supporting actor, Mark Rylance won instead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When they announced Mark Rylance for best supporting actor I’m sure everyone heard Ruffalo.  I mean besides the simple name similarity Mark Ruffalo’s performance in Spotlight was one of the best in the ensemble, whereas Rylance’s performance in Bridge of Spies barely warranted a second thought.  His character in the film may have been memorable but mostly because he was just likeable, in a film full of very forgettable characters.  Most of the credit probably goes to Joel &amp;amp; Ethan Coen’s writing rather than Rylance’s approach at the character.  I don’t really understand it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tom Hardy was by far my pick for this year.  His performance in The Revenant was a major highlight of the movie.  Leo ended up winning Best Actor – and likely deserved to – but in my eyes Hardy’s performance was the standout in that film.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;irritu-won-his-second-consecutive-best-director-award&quot;&gt;Iñárritu won his second consecutive Best Director award&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what to think here.  I would have liked to see George Miller over Iñárritu probably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;best-actor--actress&quot;&gt;Best Actor &amp;amp; Actress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Academy did alright with these picks in my eyes.  Brie Larson was the favorite going in and I’m happy she won.  She’s got likeability to her celebrity without the abrasiveness of Jennifer Lawrence’s dominance the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, Leonardo DiCaprio finally won his little gold man.  It was a long time coming.  I agree with his win this year, although I still think his first victory should have been Best Supporting Actor for his role in Django Unchained.  I’m not ecstatic, but I’m satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-rest&quot;&gt;The Rest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest was the rest, I have no complaints.  After all the ups and downs, including major Academy pitfalls, it was a fun experience.  I’ll begrudgingly be back next year, on the seat of my chair for every announcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now time to catch up on the first promising films of 2016!  &lt;em&gt;Hail, Caesar!&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Deadpool&lt;/em&gt; here I come!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/film/oscars/movies/awards/culture/2016/02/29/oscars-2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/film/oscars/movies/awards/culture/2016/02/29/oscars-2016.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>film</category>
        
        <category>oscars</category>
        
        <category>movies</category>
        
        <category>awards</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Swift Optionals...?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a simple post about my appreciation for the little things in code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m learning Swift for the first time, and I just learned about Optionals in Swift.  I just want to point out how great the syntax for an Optional is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t know, here’s the syntax for a function returning an Optional:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    func foo(isBar: Bool) -&amp;gt; String? {
      if(isBar) {
        return &quot;Bar&quot;
      }
      return nil
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just love the question mark!  Which is Swift’s way of denoting an optional return value.  It’s simple, effective, and memorable.  It gives the function personality, like it’s not quite sure if it has the String to give you or not.  Would you like a String?  Well then cough up the right Bool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s not quite so profound, but I like to see it as a good example of the greater simplicity and personality you get from Swift.  I can’t wait to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/ios/swift/development/2016/02/25/swift-optionals-are-fun.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/ios/swift/development/2016/02/25/swift-optionals-are-fun.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>ios</category>
        
        <category>swift</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>County Attorney in Arizona Boycotts iPhones and Calls Tim Cook a Terrorist Sympathizer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;…as I sigh, shudder, and forcefully slap my face with my palm yet again – my default reaction to most of the ongoing public debate over encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ars Technica will give you the details in &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/02/arizona-prosecutor-were-not-buying-any-more-iphones-over-apple-and-doj-dispute/&quot;&gt;their article&lt;/a&gt;, but let me give you the TL;DR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People don’t know what they’re talking about (big surprise) when it comes to encryption, but yet they can’t restrain themselves from talking (big surprise) about it as if they are the experts.
This blowhard prosecutor in Maricopa County, which includes Phoenix, AZ and surrounding areas, has basically said that because Apple is refusing to cooperate with the FBI’s orders to unlock an iPhone linked to a terrorist attack, they are on the terrorists’ side.  As such, they’ve decided to stop buying iPhones for the employees of their agency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more accurate description of Tim Cook’s allegiance is not to terrorists but to his customers.  Millions of which could be at risk of a loss of security if Apple is compelled to comply with the FBI’s current orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my favorite quote from this article on Ars:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If the potential for unauthorized access to an encryption key is truly motivating Apple’s unwillingness to assist in downloading information from specific iPhones, then let’s define the problem in those terms and work on that concern,” Montgomery added. “Otherwise, Apple is proving indifferent to the need for evidence to hold people accountable who have harmed or intend to harm fellow citizens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would say to Mr. Montgomery – read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/customer-letter/&quot;&gt;the letter Tim Cook wrote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my response to this logic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best way keep the key out of the wrong hands – don’t create it in the first place.  The debate &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; defined by those terms.  I would also ask who he expects to manage and protect his hypothetical key.
His argument also represents the blindness of most arguments against mine and Apple’s point of view.  There is no concern from this conservative crusader for justice that the government or law enforcement agencies could abuse, misuse, or mishandle the software or ‘key’ that the FBI demands Apple create.  This blindness to the perspective that this debate is not just a single issue where Apple stands as a barrier between law enforcement and justice in this one case – it’s an existential argument about the power of government reach and the privacy of American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verge is following this debate pretty well with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/2/17/11036306/apple-fbi-iphone-encryption-backdoor-tim-cook&quot;&gt;timeline stream&lt;/a&gt;.  I’ve also been following up with reactions to choice breaking stories and I probably will have more rage-posts in the future.  Check out the old ones &lt;a href=&quot;http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/apple/doj/fbi/2016/02/19/fbi-doj-apple-ordered-to-create-backdoor.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/2016/02/14/encryption-bill-positive.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/apple/doj/fbi/2016/02/24/encryption-blowhard-in-arizona.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/apple/doj/fbi/2016/02/24/encryption-blowhard-in-arizona.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>encryption</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>doj</category>
        
        <category>fbi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DOJ Compels Apple to Create Backdoor</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote a short post about encryption with a slightly positive twist on Monday.  That was nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Tuesday, a U.S. District court ruled that Apple must break or circumvent the security on the iPhone 5C that was involved in the San Bernardino terrorist attacks this December.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Tim Cook wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;apple.com/customer-letter&quot;&gt;open letter to customers&lt;/a&gt; where he warned customers and all of us about the dangers of this kind of request.  It’s a good read, and explains many of what have been my own concerns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the letter, the discussion has basically gone viral, blowing up this encryption discussion to a whole new level - maybe the only good news in this turn of events.  Everyone has been weighing in, including the viral maniac Donald J. Trump himself who has gone so far as to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/2/19/11071684/donald-trump-apple-boycott-encryption-iphone/in/10800347&quot;&gt;call for a boycott&lt;/a&gt; of apple products (&lt;em&gt;give me a break&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has said it will file to object the request from the FBI/DOJ, and has been granted three additional days to make it’s decision.  Ars Technica has an &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/02/how-apple-will-fight-the-doj-in-iphone-backdoor-crypto-case/&quot;&gt;interesting piece&lt;/a&gt; on how Apple will likely approach its appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This story is compelling and terrifying all at once, to myself and anyone in technology and security.  It’s also worrying as American citizens, who should be skeptical of our government’s reach in matters such as these.  The Verge &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/2/19/11064054/apple-fbi-lockscreen-encryption-passcode-backdoor/in/10800347&quot;&gt;writes at length&lt;/a&gt; about the dangers the sort of tool that Apple would build could have to the security of our devices, not just the possibility that hackers could potentially compromise and use the software to hack other devices, but even more likely and more worrying to me is that our government agencies could likely use this move as precedent to make these requests at their whim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My request for anyone reading - educate yourself on this issues.  We can’t afford to give up our privacy on an issue like this because it’s emotional.  It behooves us to think about the future and about the implications of our actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Verge is keeping track of this story as it develops &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/2/17/11036306/apple-fbi-iphone-encryption-backdoor-tim-cook&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/apple/doj/fbi/2016/02/19/fbi-doj-apple-ordered-to-create-backdoor.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/apple/doj/fbi/2016/02/19/fbi-doj-apple-ordered-to-create-backdoor.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>encryption</category>
        
        <category>apple</category>
        
        <category>doj</category>
        
        <category>fbi</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>U.S. House Introduces Bill to Protect Encryption</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Any time I’ve read an article with ‘encryption’ in the headline over the last few months I’ve had to cringe and shake my head at the mostly overwhelming ignorance of our leaders and politicians on the topic.  Any time a presidential candidate gets asked about it, any time you read about state or local legislators talking about encryption, it’s always bad news for the public and for our privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out there actually are some individuals in our government who can understand this subject and approach it intelligently.  A bi-partisan house bill from House Representatives Ted Lieu (D-Calif.) and Blake Farenthold (R-Tex.) seeks to prohibit state and local governments from creating legislation requiring devices to have weakened encryption or a ‘back-door’ for law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bill is very short, reading entirely as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A State or political subdivision of a State may not mandate or request that a manufacturer, developer, seller, or provider of covered products or services—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(1) design or alter the security functions in its product or service to allow the surveillance of any user of such product or service, or to allow the physical search of such product, by any agency or instrumentality of a State, a political subdivision of a State, or the United States; or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(2) have the ability to decrypt or otherwise render intelligible information that is encrypted or otherwise rendered unintelligible using its product or service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the quote I swiped from &lt;a href=&quot;http://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2016/02/house-bill-would-kill-state-local-bills-that-aim-to-weaken-smartphone-crypto/&quot;&gt;Ars Technica&lt;/a&gt; that I think sums up my frustration with the issue thus far:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eff.org/about/staff/andrew-crocker&quot;&gt;Andrew Crocker&lt;/a&gt;, an attorney at the Electronic Frontier Foundation, told Ars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“We also have lawmakers who are instead proposing vague and/or ineffective ‘solutions’ to that fundamental concern. That’s really the sum of these &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Crypto_Wars&quot;&gt;Crypto Wars&lt;/a&gt;: The ‘pro encryption’ side has the weight of technical and policy expertise. The ‘anti’ side repeats that it can be done without saying how.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also criticism of the bill in its succinct phrasing that devices can’t be altered or encryption weakened – when most budding legislation is looking to ban encrypted devices.  To me as a pragmatist, this is at least a solid step in the right direction.  It also helps to restore my faith in some of our legislators who I’ve begun to write off as universally out-of-touch with technical issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Color me cautiously optimistic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/2016/02/14/encryption-bill-positive.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/politics/encryption/2016/02/14/encryption-bill-positive.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>encryption</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rostam Batmanglij Leaves Vampire Weekend</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I heard the news today that Rostam was leaving Vampire Weekend from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theverge.com/2016/1/26/10833914/vampire-weekend-rostam-batmanglij-quit-band&quot;&gt;an article on The Verge&lt;/a&gt;, and I was deeply saddened.  Sad in that optimistic way where you’re happy for your friend but sad to see them go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rostam was such a big part of VW, but I’m not surprised to see him go.  He is immensely talented, and has proven his musical chops outside of the band in the past.  His collaboration with Ra Ra Riot’s Wesley Miles, Discovery, sounds like the spiritual love child of the two bands’ sounds and is one of my favorite albums of its kind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His new music has begun to trickle out as well, including a great single “EOS” which sounds like an echo of both Discovery and Vampire Weekend - in the best possible way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long story short - this is sad news for a long time Vampire Weekend fan, who would just as soon see him continue to elevate that great band, but I’m also extremely excited to see what this talented musician has in the pipeline on his own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:51:17 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://ajkueterman.com/music/2016/01/26/rostam.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ajkueterman.com/music/2016/01/26/rostam.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
